Christy Welsh

Full Stack Engineer

I am an excellent engineer and problem solver with a background in mathematics education and technical writing. Over the past year, I took the initiative to complete a full stack curriculum based in Node.JS. This opportunity added web development to my experience as a tenured teacher with a credential that includes number theory and statistics. I am a perfect fit for computer programming because I am a logical thinker, organizational guru, and self-disciplined worker, always striving for excellence and efficiency in the details.

Technical Skills:

 HTML SQL Familiarity with MySQL, PostgreSQL CSS Python **JavaScript** MongoDB Java Node.JS (React & Express) **AWS** Git · Heroku · Passport.JS **JQuery** · AWS EC2 & RDS Bootstrap, Material UI, etc. · Stripe.JS

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer, Student; Covalence, MongoDB University, Udacity, & more

2018-2019

- Created and deployed apps that integrate the elements of a full Node stack including HTML/CSS/React frontend, RESTful Express backend, and SQL or MongoDB storage.
- Designed and built apps that excel in visual presentation, usability, functionality, secure login, payment processing, access to external APIs, etc.
- Problem solved hundreds of issues that arose in each workflow stage by leveraging multiple resources including independent debug, version testing, research, collaboration on Stack Overflow, discussion on dev forums.

2015-2017

Tenured Mathematics Teacher; Castro Valley High School

- Led students to math standards mastery in new curriculum and evolving state mandates by evaluating individual learning needs, collaborating with parents and support staff, and delivering lessons one-to-one, and in small and large groups.
- Managed over 100 students per year, maintaining a positive, encouraging, and safe classroom environment of diverse youth; from at-risk to high achieving, from a wide range of socio-economic backgrounds.
- · Engaged students by integrating educational technology tools such as iPads, eBooks, graphing calculators, Desmos, etc.

Spring Semester 2015

Mathematics Teacher: Clayton Valley Charter High School

- · Quickly established positive relationships, stepping in to lead classes that experienced an inconsistent fall semester.
- Remediated students' deficient math skills by designing and implementing interactive lessons and by collaborating with parents, administrators, fellow teachers, and subject teams, resulting in nearly 90% of student advancement.

Additional Experience:

Science and Technical Writer & Copy Editor, Various freelance roles

Resource Instructional Aide & Tutor, 10 years' experience leading students elementary to college

2004-2014

Education

Full Stack Web Development, Covalence, MongoDB University, Udacity, and other online certifications
Single Subject Teaching Credential Mathematics, Patten University, Oakland, California
Technical Writing Certification, San Francisco State University
Bachelor of Arts Degree, CSU Hayward, Summa Cum Laude